A Guide to the Office of the Dean of Students Office Administrative Files, 1982-2000
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Office of the Dean of Students Office Administrative Files 1982-2000
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-18/2/1.011
This collection consists of 9,500 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions apply to personally identifiable student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library on 2001 November 29.
Scope and Content Information
Topical files from Dean Robert T. Canevari's and Dean Penny Rue's office, including the files of the V. Shamim Sisson, Associate Dean of Students.
Organization
Series I: Dean of Students-Canevari/Rue, 1982-2000 Boxes 1-14
Series II: Assistant Dean-Sisson, 1990-2001 Boxes 15-17
Series III: Restricted Files Boxes 18-19
Contents List
- Series I: Dean of Students-Robert T. Canevari and Penny Rue
  - Alcohol Task Force (2 folders) 1998 (Box 1)
  - Alcohol Task Force-Subcommittee A (2 folders) 1998 (Box 1)
  - Alcohol Task Force-Subcommittee A Originals Report 1998 (Box 1)
  - Health Behaviors Survey 1997 (Box 1)
  - Attorney General's Task Force on Drinking by College Students 1998 (Box 2)
  - Algernon Sydney Sullivan 1995-1997 (Box 2)
  - Algernon Sydney Sullivan Award Account 1993-1996 (Box 2)
  - Gus Blagden Committee 1996-1997 (Box 2)
  - Gus Blagden Committee (Restricted) 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - Gus Blagden Nominations (Restricted) 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - First Year Enrollment 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - Eating/Exercise Disorders Committee-U.Va. CARES 1996-1998 (Box 2)
  - Gray Carrington Committee (Restricted) 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - Gray Carrington Committee 1996-1997 (Box 2)
  - Gray Carrington Finalists (Restricted) 1997 (Box 2)
  - AD HOC Committee on Fraternities and Sororities 1998 (Box 2)
  - Dean of Students-Robert T. Canevari 1999 (Box 2)
  - Dean of Students-Robert T. Canevari 1997 (Box 3)
  - Historic Renovation Corporation 1997-1998 (Box 3)
  - Historic Renovation Corporation 1996-1997 (Box 3)
  - International Center Advisory Committee 1995-1998 (Box 3)
  - Lawn Selection Process Organizing Committee 1996-1997 (Box 3)
  - Lawn Organizing Committee 1997-1998 (Box 3)
  - Orientation Task Force (2 folders) 1997-1998 (Box 3)
  - Assistant Dean of Students Search-Fraternity/Sorority 1997 (Box 3)
  - Search Committee: Assistant Dean of Students (Residence Life Office) 1998 (Box 3)
  - Assistant Dean of Students Search-Orientation, Contracted Independent Organization (2 folders) 1996 (Box 4)
  - Search Committee-Assistant Dean of Students (Fraternity/Sorority) 1997 (Box 4)
  - Area Coordinator Search 1998 (Box 4)
  - Substance Abuse Studies Council 1997-1998 (Box 4)
  - Vice President Committee on University Union and Student Activities Buildings 1996-1997 (Box 4)
  - University Union and Student Activities Building Committee 1997-1998 (Box 4)
  - University Union-Programs and Budgets 1998-1999 (Box 4)
  - Admissions Office 1995-1997 (Box 4)
  - Applicants for Admissions-Letters of Support (Restricted 2 folders) 1996-1998 (Box 4)
  - Office of African American Affairs 1996-1997 (Box 4)
  - Center for Multi-Ethnic and Cultural Affairs 1997 (Box 4)
  - Alcohol-Alcohol Free Dorms Proposal 1994 (Box 4)
  - Box 5
  - Alcohol Awareness/Miscellaneous (Restricted) 1994-1996 (Box 5)
  - Alumni Association Miscellaneous 1996-1997 (Box 5)
  - Ernest H. Ern Award 1993-1996 (Box 5)
  - Board of Visitors 1997-1998 (Box 5)
  - Theresa Carroll Project 1997 (Box 5)
  - AD HOC Committee on Classroom Disruptions 1996-1997 (Box 5)
  - Contracted Independent Organizations and Fraternal Organizational Agreement 1990-1996 (Box 5)
  - President's Convocation (Orientation) 1993-1996 (Box 5)
  - President's Retreat/Family Weekend 1996-1997 (Box 5)
  - Travel Approval Forms 1994-1998 (Box 5)
  - Office of Dean of Students Emergency on Call 1995-1997 (Box 5)
  - Consulting-Dean of Students 1994-1995 (Box 5)
  - Office of Dean of Students Staff Meetings 1997-1998 (Box 5)
  - Records Management 1984-1995 (Box 5)
  - Assistant to the Dean of Students (Establishment of the Position) 1996 (Box 6)
  - History of University Seminar 1994-1996 (Box 6)
  - Dean Canevari's Speeches 1998-1999 (Box 6)
  - Program Budgets (2 folders) 1996-1997 (Box 6)
  - Office of Dean of Students Miscellaneous 1998-1999 (Box 6)
  - Office of Dean of Students Miscellaneous 1997-1998 (Box 6)
  - 1-10830 DATS Information 1996-1997 (Box 6)
  - Budget (Office of Dean of Students, Residence Life, Student Activities Business Manager) 1996-1997 (Box 6)
  - Budget (Dean of Students, Residence Life Office, Student Activities Business Manager) 1997-1998 (Box 6)
  - Family Weekend/ President's Retreat 4-10830 1997-1998 (Box 7)
  - Office of Dean of Students Interns 1997-1998 (Box 7)
  - Interns (Office of Dean of Students) 1998 (Box 7)
  - DATS Information 1-10830 1997-1998 (Box 7)
  - Class Organization Meetings 1997-1998 (Box 7)
  - Class of 1997 1997 (Box 7)
  - Class of 1998 1998 (Box 7)
  - Faculty/Staff Campaign 1996-1998 (Box 7)
  - Faculty Reimbursement 1991-1997 (Box 7)
  - Stillfried/Godsey Scholarship 1996-1997 (Box 7)
  - Award for Stillfried/Godsey 1997-1998 (Box 7)
  - Finals-Policy on Demonstrations 1992-1993 (Box 7)
  - First Year Council 1991-1996 (Box 7)
  - Fraternity Alumni Council 1996-1997 (Box 8)
  - Fraternities 1993-1997 (Box 8)
  - Honor Committee 1996-1997 (Box 8)
  - Honor Committee 1997-1998 (Box 8)
  - Housing Division 1995-1997 (Box 8)
  - Planning and Assessment Off Grounds Student Survey 1996 (Box 8)
  - Portfolio Project: Ankur 1997 (Box 8)
  - Portfolio Project Institutional Assessment and Studies 1997 (Box 8)
  - Housing Division External Review 1997 (Box 8)
  - Vice President Task Force on Housing 1996 (Box 8)
  - Health Behaviors Survey U.Va. Undergraduate Students 1996 (Box 8)
  - Health Behaviors Survey U.Va. Undergraduate Students 1997 (Box 8)
  - Lower Lawn Reservations 1997-1998 (Box 8)
  - Lower Lawn Reservations 1998-1999 (Box 8)
  - The Lawn Miscellaneous 1995-1997 (Box 8)
  - Leadership 2000 1997 (Box 9)
  - Women's Leadership 1997 (Box 9)
  - Madison House 1991-1997 (Box 9)
  - Alcohol Possession, Football Games (Restricted) 1997 (Box 9)
  - Inter-Fraternity Council 1997-1998 (Box 9)
  - Inter-Sorority Council 1996-1997 (Box 9)
  - University Mediation Services 1996-1997 (Box 9)
  - Judiciary Committee 1996-1997 (Box 9)
  - Judiciary Committee 1997-1998 (Box 9)
  - Kaleidoscope (2 folders) 1997 (Box 9)
  - Interracial/Multi-Ethnic Student Group 1993-1994 (Box 9)
  - Multi-Ethnic Interracial Forum 1994-1995 (Box 9)
  - Multi-Ethnic/Interracial 1995 (Box 9)
  - Multi-Ethnic Interracial Handouts (2 folders) 1992-1996 (Box 10)
  - The Cavalier Daily 1988-1997 (Box 10)
  - Newspaper Articles 1998-1999 (Box 10)
  - Newspaper Articles 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Newcomb Hall Banner Policy 1998 (Box 10)
  - John Herring-Support for the Arts 1996 (Box 10)
  - Orientation 1997 (Box 10)
  - Grounds for Discussion 1996 (Box 10)
  - Orientation/OASIS 1998 (Box 10)
  - Grounds for Discussion 1997 (Box 11)
  - Parents Funding Disbursements 1996-1997 (Box 11)
  - Parents Committee Proposals for Funding 1996-1997 (Box 11)
  - Parents Funding 1997 (Box 11)
  - Performance Space 1996-1997 (Box 11)
  - Student Performance Groups 1997-1998 (Box 11)
  - Parents Weekend 1995-1996 (Box 11)
  - Planning and Assessment: Assessment Dean of Students Programs (2 folders) 1993-1994 (Box 11)
  - President's Office (Casteen) 1993-1998 (Box 12)
  - President's Retreat (2 folders) 1996 (Box 12)
  - President's Retreat (2 folders) 1997 (Box 12)
  - Residence Life Office 1996-1997 (Box 12)
  - Resident Staff 1991-1997 (Box 12)
  - Residence Life Office 1997-1998 (Box 12)
  - Resident Staff 1997-1998 (Box 12)
  - Residence Life-Fires (Dorms) 1995 (Box 12)
  - Residential Life Plan 1982 (Box 12)
  - Resident Coordinator Metcalf/Lefevre 1998-1999 (Box 13)
  - Self Study: Criteria for Accreditation 1995 (Box 13)
  - Accreditation Process 1996 (Box 13)
  - Targeting Excellence-U.Va. Self Study 1994-1996 (Box 13)
  - Report of Compliance-U.Va. Self Study 1994-1996 (Box 13)
  - University Self Study 1984 (Box 13)
  - Student Activities Committee 1995-1996 (Box 13)
  - Student Affairs Retreat 1997 (Box 13)
  - Student Council 1997-1998 (Box 13)
  - Student Council 1996-1997 (Box 13)
  - Student Council Spirit Days 1996-1997 (Box 13)
  - William Harmon, Vice President for Student Affairs 1996-1997 (Box 13)
  - Vice President for Student Affairs Staff Meetings 1997-1998 (Box 14)
  - Vice President for Student Affairs Staff Meetings 1998-1999 (Box 14)
  - University Police Department 1995-1997 (Box 14)
  - Campus and Workplace Violence Report (Janet Warren) 1996 (Box 14)
  - University Union 1996-1997 (Box 14)
  - Pavilion XI Philosophy Statement 1988 (Box 14)
  - University Union 1997-1998 (Box 14)
  - Women's Center Grant Proposal 1997 (Box 14)
- Series II: Assistant Dean-Shamim Sisson
  - Alcohol Task Force-Subcommittee 1998 (Box 15)
  - Alcohol Task Force-Subcommittee B Folder A (2 folders) 1998 (Box 15)
  - Alcohol Task Force-Subcommittee B Folder B (2 folders) 1998 (Box 15)
  - Asian American Assistant Dean Search 2001 (Box 15)
  - Class of 1989 Exit Interviews 1989 (Box 15)
  - Dean on Call Manuals 1998-2000 (Box 16)
  - Experiences of African American Students at U.Va 1990-1993 (Box 16)
  - First Year Seminar 1999-2000 (Box 16)
  - First Year Seminar (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 16)
  - First Year Seminar-Reservations/Financial 2000 (Box 16)
  - First Year Seminar-Applications (Restricted) 1999-2000 (Box 16)
  - First Year Seminar-Participant Evaluations (Restricted) 2000 (Box 16)
  - First Year Seminar-Exit Interviews 2000 (Box 16)
  - First Year Seminar-Exit Interviews Instructional Teams (Restricted) 1999 (Box 16)
  - First Year Seminar-Participant Evaluations (Restricted) 1999 (Box 16)
  - Melissa Holland Award Nominations (Restricted) 1998-1999 (Box 16)
  - Melissa Holland Award (Restricted) 2000 (Box 16)
  - Last Word Project 1999 (Box 16)
  - Leadership 2000 (3 folders) 2000 (Box 16)
  - Leadership 2000-Reservations/Financial 1999 (Box 17)
  - Leadership 2000-Meals 2001 (Box 17)
  - Leadership 2000-Evaluations 1999 (Box 17)
  - Office of African American Affairs Task Force 1996-1997 (Box 17)
  - Parent's Orientation 1999 (Box 17)
  - Phi Eta Sigma 1999 (Box 17)
  - Student Government, Organizations, and Media 1999 (Box 17)
  - Women's Leadership Development Program 1999-2000 (Box 17)
  - Women's Leadership Development Program-Registration 2000 (Box 17)
  - Women's Leadership Development Program-Nominations 2001 (Box 17)
  - Women's Leadership Development Program-Committee Applications (Restricted) 1999-2000 (Box 17)
  - Women's Leadership Development Program-Session I 2000 (Box 17)
  - Women's Leadership Development Program-Reservations/Financial 1999-2000 (Box 17)
  - Women's Leadership Development Program-Session II 2000 (Box 17)
  - Women's Leadership Development Program-Final Dinner 2000 (Box 17)
- Series III: Restricted Files (Box 18-19)